Guide to the Charles Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- TOPICAL FILES, 1916-(1918-1919)-1959; Series III; 2 linear feet (8 boxes)
  - Peace Conference
    - Commission for the Study of Roumanian Territorial Questions
      - Session 2, 1919 February 11 (Box 60, Folder 3)
      - Session 3, 1919 February 13 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      - Session 4, 1919 February 17 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Session 5, 1919 February 19 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      - Session 6, 1919 February 22 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Commission for the Study of Territorial Questions Relating to Roumania and Jugo-Slavia
      - Session 7, 1919 February 25 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      - Session 8, 1919 February (Box 60, Folder 9)
      - Session 9, 1919 March 2 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      - Session 10, 1919 March 3 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      - Session 11, 1919 March 6 (Box 60, Folder 12)
      - Session 12, 1919 March 7 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Session 13, 1919 March 10 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Session 14, 1919 March 11 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - Session 15, 1919 March 11 (Box 60, Folder 16)
      - Session 16, 1919 March 13 (Box 60, Folder 17)
      - Session 17, 1919 March 18 (Box 60, Folder 18)
      - Session 18, 1919 March 25 (Box 60, Folder 19)
      - Session 19, 1919 March 29 (Box 60, Folder 20)
      - Session 20, 1919 April 3 (Box 60, Folder 21)
      - Report No. 1, 1919 April 6 (Box 60, Folder 21a)
    - Committee on Tchecho-Slovak Questions, Report, 1919 March 12 (Box 60, Folder 21b)
    - Austria, German: Anschluss Question (Box 61, Folder 22)
    - Austria, German: Recommendation as to boundaries (Box 61, Folder 23)
    - Austria, German: Delegation to the Peace Conference [A. C. Coolidge to W. E. Bundy], 1919 May 12 (Box 61, Folder 24)
    - Austria: Racial distribution: Slovenes - Serbocroats (Box 61, Folder 25)
    - Austria: Treaty with, Proposed articles for treaty (Box 61, Folder 26)
    - Austria, German: miscellaneous papers (Box 61, Folder 27)
    - Austria: Austrian Alps, Industrial distribution maps (Box 61, Folder 28)
    - Austria: Carinthia, Memorandum on the Frontiers of German-Austria (Box 61, Folder 29)
    - Austria: Carinthia, Gorice, and Carniola, Map: Italian Claims and Wilson's Principles (Box 61, Folder 30)
    - Austria: Carinthia, Terms of armistice between Austria and Jugo-Slavia re: provisional occupation of Carinthia, 1919 June 6 (Box 61, Folder 31)
    - Austria: Carinthia, Provisional line of demarcation [Miles and King to A. C. Coolidge], 1919 February 7 (Box 61, Folder 32)
    - Austria: Carinthia, two ethnographic maps in color (Box 61, Folder 33)
    - Austria: Klagenfurt Basin, opinions of members of American Commission (Box 61, Folder 34)
    - Austria: Klagenfurt, miscellaneous papers (Box 61, Folder 35)
    - Austria: Steiermark, two maps, alternate boundaries marked in crayon (Box 61, Folder 36)
    - Austria-Hungary (Empire): Extracts from statements of President Wilson concerning Austria-Hungary (Box 61, Folder 37)
    - Austro-Hungarian and Yugo-Slav Countries: Daily Bulletins, 1919 January-March (Box 61, Folder 38-40)
    - Austria-Hungary: miscellaneous [Seymour - Bullitt - Dulles] (Box 61, Folder 41)
    - Austria-Hungary: miscellaneous papers, map (Box 61, Folder 42)
    - Balkans: Report on current events, 1919 January (Box 61, Folder 43)
    - Baranja: Economic reasons why it should be united with the kingdom of the Serbs, Croats, and Slovenes (Box 61, Folder 44)
    - Baranya: miscellaneous papers (Box 61, Folder 45)
    - Central Europe: the political situation in (weekly summaries prepared by A. W. Dulles), 1919 January-March (Box 61, Folder 46)
    - Central Europe: the political situation in (weekly summaries prepared by R. J. Kerner), 1919 March-May (Box 61, Folder 47)
    - Czechoslovakia: Map showing boundaries of "Czecho-Slovonian" State (Box 61, Folder 48)
    - Czechoslovakia: Czechoslovakian Financial Situation, typed article in French with card of E. Benes (Box 61, Folder 49)
    - Czechoslovakia: Czecho-Slovaks in History, Abstracted from "Language and Sentiment of Nationality" by C. D. Buck (Box 61, Folder 50)
    - Czechoslovakia: Population statistics and ethnological map (Box 61, Folder 51)
    - Czechoslovakia: Czech attitude, Stoddard, "Present Day Europe" (Box 61, Folder 52)
    - Czechoslovakia: Czech demands, Abstracts from "The Heart of Europe" by Pergler (Box 61, Folder 53)
    - Czechoslovakia: Czech demands since 1914, abstracted from "The Demands of the Bohemian People" in Journal of Race Development, 1917 October (Box 61, Folder 54)
    - Czechoslovakia: Conversation: General Smuts and President Masaryk, Czechoslovak frontiers, 1919 April 7 (Box 61, Folder 55)
    - Czechoslovakia: Bohemia, miscellaneous papers (Czecho-Slovakia) (Box 62, Folder 56)
    - Czechoslovakia: Bohemia, The Germans of; statement, Eduard Benes (Czecho-Slovakia), 1919 June 19 (Box 62, Folder 57)
    - Czechoslovakia: Mamaros and Vgocsa (Czecho-Slovakia) Ethnological statistics, map (Box 62, Folder 58)
    - Czechoslovakia: Ruthenians in Czecho-Slovakia, memorandum, undated (Box 62, Folder 59)
    - Czechoslovakia: Teschen Commission, Interallied, 1919 Mar, April (Box 62, Folder 60)
    - Czechoslovakia: Teschen Question, statement of Mr. Du Bois, 1919 May 16 (Box 62, Folder 61)
    - Czechoslovakia: Teschen, wishes of population of; memorandum of Czechoslovak delegation and comments by R. J. Kerner, 1919 April 2 (Box 62, Folder 62)
    - Czechoslovakia: miscellaneous papers (Box 62, Folder 63)
    - Germany: German Delegation, observations on the conditions of peace, 1919 June 4 (Box 62, Folder 64)
    - Germany, Southern Boundary of: Recommendations - Seymour (Box 62, Folder 65)
    - Germany: German Frontiers; meeting of American and British representatives, 1919 February 21 (Box 62, Folder 66)
    - Germany: German Frontiers; discussion of draft terms concerning, (1919 Feb?) (Box 62, Folder 67)
    - Germany: Magyars in Germany (Deutscher Erde), 1911 (Box 62, Folder 68)
    - Germany: Glatz, City of; telegram (to Wilson) from the people of Glatz requesting to remain a part of the German Empire (Box 62, Folder 69)
    - Germany: Tyrol, German; miscellaneous papers (Box 62, Folder 70)
    - Hungary: Maps; four sets of maps of Northern, Eastern, Southern, and West-central Hungary, indicating relief, population density, and nationalities (Box 62, Folder 71)
    - Hungary: Ruthenians of Hungary; report of the Czechoslovak committee on form of autonomy, 1919 May 22 (Box 62, Folder 72)
    - Hungary: Serbs; "Les Serbes de Hongrie," by E. Picot (abstracts) (Box 62, Folder 73)
    - Hungary: miscellaneous statistics (Box 62, Folder 74)
    - Italy: Italian Claims; letter of Division Heads to President Wilson, 1919 April 17 (Box 62, Folder 75)
    - Italy: Italian Irredentism; abstracted from L'Italia Irredenta by Jean Pozzi, in Revue des Deux Mondes, 1915 February 1 (Box 62, Folder 76)
    - Italy: Italian Irredenta; five memoranda, Sonnino (Box 62, Folder 77)
    - Italy: The Italo-Jugoslav Question explained by maps; memorandum, 1919 January 25 (Box 62, Folder 78)
    - Italy: Italo-Jugoslav boundary: Goritz; memoranda by Anton Korosek (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 79)
    - Italy: Adriatic; La Question de l'Adriatique by Charles Vellay (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 80)
    - Italy: Adriatic: Dalmatia, Fiume, etc.; miscellaneous papers, map (Box 62, Folder 81)
    - Italy: Adriatic ports; trade statistics (Box 62, Folder 82)
    - Italy: Racial and Political Problem in Adriatic Lands, The; abstracted from "The Problem of the Adriatic," by J. A. R. Marriott (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 83)
    - Italy: Fiume and Dalmatia; notes of Charles Seymour to President Wilson (Italy), undated (Box 62, Folder 84)
    - Italy: Fiume, draft articles regarding (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 85)
    - Italy: Fiume; municipal autonomy of Reka in recent times, from 1870 to 1918 (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 86)
    - Italy: Trentino; geographical, economic, military, ethnographic (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 87)
    - Italy: Trentino; miscellaneous papers (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 88)
    - Italy: Trieste; memorandum by Gustavis Gregorin (Italy) (Box 62, Folder 89)
    - Jugoslavia: four maps: population, languages, religions, geographical regions (Box 62, Folder 90)
    - Jugoslavia: Fiume; Italian agression, 1919 January (Box 62, Folder 91)
    - Jugoslavia and German Austria: Recommended change in frontier [Day and Seymour to the Commissioners], 1919 May 22 (Box 62, Folder 92)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs, Attitude of; T. L. Stoddard, "Present Day Europe" (Box 62, Folder 93)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs, Austrian; national history and traditions, undated (Box 62, Folder 94)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugo-Slavs; dossier, Federated Societies of (Jugo-Slav) College Students in Switzerland, 1919 January 9 (Box 62, Folder 95)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs in Italy, sketch of the demands for the protection of (Box 62, Folder 96)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs, Serbs and Croats; Krmpotic, "On Great Serbia" (Box 62, Folder 97)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs; statistical data (Box 62, Folder 98)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs; "The Yugo-Slavs," from H. W. Stead, "A Program for Peace" (Box 62, Folder 99)
    - Jugoslavia: Jugoslavs; "The Yugo-Slavs," abstracted from "Language and Sentiment of Nationality," by C. O. Burk in American Political Science Review (Box 62, Folder 100)
    - Poland: Les Protestants Polonais et la Question des Frontieres Occidentales de la Pologne (Box 63, Folder 101)
    - Roumania: Attitude Toward Peace Conference; letter, Seymour to Auchincloss, 1919 February 14 (Box 63, Folder 102)
    - Roumania: Roumanian Preponderance in Transylvania, Hungary, and the Banat (Box 63, Folder 103)
    - Roumania: Banat and Backa; map in color showing percentages of languages (Box 63, Folder 104)
    - Roumania: Banat; Examen des Pretentions Serbes sur le Banat de Temeshvar (Box 63, Folder 105)
    - Roumania: Banat, navigable waterways in (Roumania) (Box 63, Folder 106)
    - Roumania: Banat, Serbian; invasion of (Box 63, Folder 107)
    - Roumania: Banat; statements of the Italian Delegation, maps (Box 63, Folder 108)
    - Roumania: Banat; miscellaneous papers (Box 63, Folder 109)
    - Daily Bulletin - Austro-Hungarian and Yugo-Slav Countries, 1919 January 16 - March 7 (Box 63, Folder 110)
    - Daily Bulletin - Austro-Hungarian and Yugo-Slav Countries, 1919 March 8 -April 23 (Box 63, Folder 111)
    - Weekly summary - German-Austria, Hungary and Bohemia, 1919 January 11, 18 (Box 63, Folder 112)
    - Confidential memorandum by Henry White re: Bernstorff, 1919 (Box 63, Folder 113)
    - Unsigned memorandum re: Socialist and Labor parties of the Entente, [c. 1918] (Box 63, Folder 114)
    - Miscellaneous maps, [1919] (Box 63, Folder 115-117)
  - General
    - "Aux Grands Injustes de la Conference de la Paix", [1919 May 18?] (Box 64, Folder 117a)
    - La Commission des Archives de la Guerre, 1923 (Box 64, Folder 118)
    - Craufurd - Stuart Affair (Box 64, Folder 119)
    - Westbrook Pegler Articles re: Colonel House and Philip Dru, 1954-1955 (Box 64, Folder 120)
    - Interview with Colonel House by William Allen White, 1924 April 24 (Box 64, Folder 121)
    - Bibliography: The Subversion of German Idealism (Box 64, Folder 122)
    - American Intervention, Memorandum on Materials Dealing with (Box 64, Folder 123)
    - "The Sinking of the Lusitania " Bibliography (Box 64, Folder 124)
    - "The Sinking of the Lusitania" Excerpts from Captain Schwieger's Log and Fregattenkapitan Bauer's Diary (Box 64, Folder 125)
    - "The Sinking of the Lusitania " Early draft of Thomas A. Bailey article in American Historical Review XLI (October 25), pp. 54-73. (Box 64, Folder 126)
    - Neutrality, Draft of statement re: (J. P. Morgan Company reply to the Nye Committee), [c. 1936] (Box 64, Folder 127)
    - Neutrality, quotations concerning (J. P. Morgan Company response to Nye Committee), 1916, 1919-1920 (Box 64, Folder 128)
    - Neutrality, memoranda concerning (J. P. Morgan Company response to Nye Committee), 1935 March-November (Box 64, Folder 129-130)
    - Neutrality, memoranda re: (J. P. Morgan Company response to Nye Committee), 1936-1937 (Box 64, Folder 131)
    - Neutrality, memoranda concerning (J. P. Morgan Company response to Nye Committee), undated (Box 64, Folder 132)
    - Re: Neutrality - Congressional Record, 1936 January 16-18 (Box 64, Folder 133-135)
    - Re: Neutrality - State Department and White House Communications, 1914-1915 (Box 64, Folder 136)
    - Re: Neutrality - State Department and White House Communications, 1916 January-October - 1917 (Box 65, Folder 137-138)
    - Miscellaneous Private Papers of P. J. N. B., undated (Box 65, Folder 139)
    - State Councils of Defense, 1917 (Box 65, Folder 140)
    - Notes on The Wilson Era by Josephus Daniels, 1946 (Box 65, Folder 141)
    - E. N. Hurley manuscript on Wilson (Box 65, Folder 142)
    - "Wilson's Latin American Treaties" by Carlos Castro-Ruiz, Chile, 1927 March (Box 65, Folder 143)
    - Authors' complimentary copies of articles re: World War I and Wilson, 1952-1953, 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 65, Folder 144)
    - Miscellaneous notes from other books re: Wilson and the War, undated (Box 65, Folder 145)
  - History Department
    - Bridgwater, Dorothy D. "The British Blockade Policy in the European War", undated (Box 65a, Folder 145a)
    - Crittenden, C. C. "Secret Peace Negotiations During the World War,", 1926 January (Box 65a, Folder 145b)
    - Eckels, George "Secret Peace Negotiations", 1935 June 1 (Box 65a, Folder 145c)
    - Henning, Basil Duke "The Quadruple Alliance", undated (Box 65a, Folder 145)
    - Mather, Amy L. "Woodrow Wilson and Italian War Aims", 1933 May (Box 65a, Folder 145e)
    - Micheles, Vera "Effect of the Russian Revolution on War Diplomacy,", undated (Box 65a, Folder 145)
    - Raach, J. H. "The Press as a Leader of Public Opinion During Certain Phases of the World War, 1914-1917", undated (Box 65a, Folder 145g)
    - Turisco, Frances E. "German Conspiracies During the Period of American Neutrality 1914-1917", 1937 June (Box 65a, Folder 145h)
    - Attendance and grade books, 1926-1928, undated (Box 65b, Folder 145i)
      The materials in this box are closed to research until 2009.
    - Grades, History 45a and 45b, 1926-1934 (Box 65b, Folder 145j)
    - Administrative papers, 1913-1917 (Box 65b, Folder 145k)
- PERSONAL AND MEMORABILIA, 1891-1963; Series IV; 1.5 l inear feet (5 boxes)
  This series contains a wide variety of material relating to Seymour's personal life. The material begins with Seymour family genealogical information [Transferred to the Seymour Family Papers, MS 440] and is arranged chronologically. (An exception is the King's College Alumni Reports spanning 1948-1962, which are placed with the other Cambridge University material ca. 1901-1904.). There is no box 71 in the series. The photographs that were in box 71 were transferred to the Seymour Family Papers.
  - Seymour family letters containing genealogical information
  - Miscellaneous papers re: Seymour Genealogy
  - Pamphlets concerning the Seymour family, 1891, 1908
  - Genealogy: descendents of Charles Law
  - Recollections by various relatives of life in Hudson, Ohio, undated
  - Recollections of childhood and youth
  - Early writings, 1895, 1900, 1901 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Examinations at Cambridge, 1901-1904 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Lecture notes from Cambridge, 1903 (Box 66, Folder 9a)
  - Life at Cambridge (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Cambridge: miscellaneous essays and papers (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Memo Books, [c. 1904] (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Cambridge memorabilia (social) (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Cambridge memorabilia (clubs) (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Cambridge memorabilia (financial) (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Cambridge: King's College Alumni Reports, 1948-1955, 1957-1962 (Box 67, Folder 16-19)
  - Miscellaneous reviews of Electoral Reform in England and Wales, 1915-1916 (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Peace Conference memorabilia, 1917-1919 (Box 67, Folder 21-21a)
  - Map of northwestern Europe, 1918 (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Maps of Paris and northeastern France, (c. 1919) (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Fragments of stained glass from Soissons Cathedral, spent shells, etc., 1919 (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Publishing contracts, 1919-1935 (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Charles Seymour bookplates, 1923, 1928 (Box 68, Folder 26)
  - Memorabilia of year spent in Belgium, 1924
  - Wiggin and Dana: Financial records, 1929-1941, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 28)
  - Outlines for History Seminars, 1929-1932, 1934-1937, undated (Box 68, Folder 29-29a)
  - Statement to the press by Colonel House on the appointment of Charles Seymour as President of Yale, 1937 (Box 68, Folder 30)
  - Mementoes of the Inauguration of Charles Seymour as President of Yale, 1937 (Box 68, Folder 31)
  - Scrapbook: Seymour as President of Yale (Box 68, Folder 32)
  - Pages and loose items from earlier scrapbook re: Seymour as President of Yale (Box 68, Folder 33)
  - Statement of the Corporation, Yale University, re: maintenance of the liberal arts during wartime, 1942 (Box 68, Folder 33a)
  - Miscellaneous programs, 1938-1944, 1949-1953 (Box 68, Folder 34-35)
  - President's Discretionary Fund, 1949-1950 (Box 69, Folder 36)
  - President's Report: draft, 1950 (Box 69, Folder 37-38)
  - Memorabilia of Seymour's retirement from Yale Presidency, 1950 (Box 69, Folder 39)
  - Copy of Greetings from University of Cambridge on the occasion of Yale's 250th anniversary, 1951 (Box 69, Folder 40)
  - Testimony before Loyalty Board of the Federal Security Agency on behalf of Dr. J. P. Peters, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 41)
  - Miscellaneous post-retirement memorabilia, 1952-1956, undated
  - The Patrizates, 1949-1952, 1955-1957, 1959, 1961, undated (Box 69, Folder 43-44)
  - Appointment book, 1952, 1955-1957
  - Appointment book, 1958-1963
  - Confidential memorandum on the selection of the President of Yale University, 1950, 1963 May 9 (Box 70, Folder 55)
  - Charles Seymour's Doyle-Oppenheim Collection (given to Yale University Library) (Box 70, Folder 56)
  - Rhodes Trust Interviews, undated (Box 70, Folder 57)
  - Sign commemorating Seymour's seventy-fifth birthday, 1960 (Box 70, Folder 58)
  - "In Time to Come." A Play by Howard Koch and John Huston. (Box 70, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 70, Folder 60)
  - Dedication by Ferdinand Czernin of Versailles 1919 to the memory of Charles Seymour, 1963 November (Box 70, Folder 61)
  - Assorted medals and medallions (Box 70a, Folder 61)
- PRINTED MATERIAL, 1895, 1915-(1919)-1963; Series V; 4.5 linear feet (12 boxes)
  This series is divided into three sections:
  Clippings (3 boxes)
  This section consists of newspaper clippings, some of which are mounted. The material is arranged chronologically.
  Pamphlets (7 boxes)
  This section is made up of pamphlets saved by Seymour from the Paris Peace Conference of 1919. Those pamphlets containing general information for the members of the American Commission to Negotiate Peace are at the beginning of the section. They are followed by pamphlets of a propagandist nature which were published by various national interest groups. This material is arranged alphabetically by country or region. Miscellaneous pamphlets bearing no relation to the Peace Conference nor to each other are placed at the end of the section.
  Authors' Complimentary Copies (2 boxes)
  Complimentary copies of books which were presented to Seymour because of his aid in the composition, his interest in the subject, or his friendship with the author comprise this section. The books are arranged alphabetically by the name of the author.
  - Clippings
    - World War I, 1914-1918 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Clippings from Yale Daily News, 1916 (Box 72, Folder 1a)
    - Reviews of books written by Seymour, 1916-1936, undated (Box 72, Folder 1b)
    - Peace Conference, 1918, 1919 January 1-27, February 4-March 31 (Box 72, Folder 1c-12)
    - Peace Conference, 1919 April 1-May 10,13 - June 11,13-18, July 23, November 19 (Box 73, Folder 13-20)
    - Clippings re: Charles Seymour, 1920-1942 (Box 73, Folder 20a)
    - re: What Really Happened at Paris, 1921 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - General, 1924-1927, 1929-1930, 1933 (Box 73, Folder 22-23)
    - re: American Diplomacy during the World War, 1934-1935 (Box 73, Folder 24)
    - re: American Neutrality 1914-1917, 1935-1936, undated (Box 73, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1937-1940 (Box 73, Folder 26-29)
    - Miscellaneous, 1941-1947, 1949-1952, 1956, 1959-1960, 1963, undated (Box 74, Folder 30-37)
  - Pamphlets
    - The Principal Declarations Respecting Terms of Peace by President Wilson and the Secretary of State (Box 75, Folder 38)
    - Pamphlets for the American Commission to Negotiate Peace: miscellaneous information (Box 75, Folder 39)
    - L'Atlas du Congrès (Box 75, Folder 40)
    - Re: Adriatic: Dalmatia (Box 75, Folder 41)
    - Re: Adriatic: Fiume (Box 75, Folder 42)
    - The Adriatic Review: miscellaneous copies, 1918-1919 (Box 75, Folder 43)
    - Re: Adriatic: miscellaneous (Box 75, Folder 44)
    - Re: Armenia (Box 75, Folder 45)
    - Re: Austria-Hungary (Box 75, Folder 46)
    - Re: The Balkans and Southeastern Europe (Box 75, Folder 47)
    - Re: The Banat and Baranya (Box 75, Folder 48)
    - Re: The Banat: Roumanians and Serbs (Box 76, Folder 49)
    - Re: Belgium (Box 76, Folder 50)
    - Re: Bessarabia (Box 76, Folder 51)
    - Re: Bohemia (Box 76, Folder 52)
    - Re: Bosnia (Box 76, Folder 53)
    - Re: Bulgaria (Box 76, Folder 54)
    - Re: Bulgarians in Occupied Serbia (Box 76, Folder 55)
    - Re: Bulgarians in Occupied Serbia (Box 76, Folder 56)
    - Bulgarians in their Historical, Ethnographical, and Political Frontiers
      See: box 87
    - Re: Carthinia (Box 76, Folder 57)
    - Re: Central Europe (Box 77, Folder 58)
    - Re: Chino-Japanese Negotiations, 1915 (Box 77, Folder 59)
    - Croatian National Council, Memorandum from (Box 77, Folder 60)
    - Re: The Curzon Note (August 11, 1923) and M. Poincarè's Reply (August 22, 1923) (Box 77, Folder 61)
    - Czecho-Slovak Delegation, re: Claims of Serbs of Lusatia (Box 77, Folder 62)
    - Re: Czecho-Slovakian territorial claims (Box 77, Folder 63)
    - Re: The Czecho-Slovaks (Box 77, Folder 64)
    - Re: Dobroudja (Box 77, Folder 65)
    - Re: The Dodecanese (Box 77, Folder 66-67)
    - Re: East Prussia (Box 77, Folder 68)
    - Re: Galicia, the Roman Catholic Population in the Polish-Ruthenian section of (Box 77, Folder 69)
    - Re: Germans in Bohemia, Moravia, and Silesia (Box 78, Folder 70)
    - Re: Gorice (Box 78, Folder 71)
    - Re: Greece (Box 78, Folder 72)
    - Re: Greeks in Turkey (Box 78, Folder 73)
    - Re: Hungary (Box 78, Folder 74-75)
    - Re: Italy (Box 78, Folder 76)
    - Re: Italy and France (Box 78, Folder 77)
    - Re: Italy and Yugoslavia (Box 78, Folder 78)
    - Re: Kärtner Region (Box 78, Folder 79)
    - Re: Klagenfurth (Box 78, Folder 80)
    - Re: The Lems, Slavs of Danubian Provenance (Box 78, Folder 81)
    - Re: Limburg and the Scheldt Question (Box 78, Folder 82)
    - Re: Lithuania (and White Ruthenia) (Box 78, Folder 83)
    - Re: Macedonia (Box 78, Folder 84)
    - Re: Manchuria: Report of the Commission of Enquiry Appointed by the League of Nations, 1932 (Box 78, Folder 85)
    - Re: Montenegro (Box 78, Folder 86)
    - Re: Poland and Lithuania (Box 78, Folder 87)
    - Re: Poland's territorial problems (Box 79, Folder 88)
    - Re: Roumania (Box 79, Folder 89-90)
    - Re: Roumanians of Serbia and Bulgaria (Box 79, Folder 91)
    - Re: The Rumanian Question in Siebenbürgen and Hungary, 1895 (Box 79, Folder 92)
    - Re: Salonika (Box 79, Folder 93)
    - Re: Schleswig (Box 79, Folder 94)
    - Re: Scutari (Box 79, Folder 95)
    - Re: Serbia (Box 79, Folder 96)